Guide to the John Sylvester Fischer Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1928-1978, undated; Series I; 10.5 linear feet (25 boxes)
  - Oakes, John B. and Marjery (*), 1947-1950,1965-1978 (Box 17, Folder 561)
  - Oc-Of (Box 17, Folder 562)
  - O'Donnell, Terence, 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 563)
  - Og-Oke (Box 17, Folder 564)
  - Ogburn, Charleton, Jr. (*), 1967-1972 (Box 17, Folder 565-567)
  - Okl (Box 17, Folder 568)
  - Oklahoma, University of (*), 1928-1931,1968-1973 (Box 17, Folder 569)
  - Old-Olm (Box 17, Folder 570)
  - Ols (Box 17, Folder 571)
  - Op-Or (Box 17, Folder 572)
  - Os-Overb (Box 17, Folder 573)
  - Osborne, John (*), 1946-1951 (Box 17, Folder 574)
  - Overs-Ox (Box 17, Folder 575)
  - 'O' unidentified (Box 17, Folder 576)
  - P-Padd (Box 17, Folder 577)
  - Padf-Pale (Box 17, Folder 578)
  - Palm-Pap (Box 17, Folder 579)
  - Para-Parr (Box 17, Folder 580)
  - Parrish, Mary (*), 1950-1953 (Box 17, Folder 581)
  - Part-Pat (Box 17, Folder 582)
  - Pau-Pea (Box 17, Folder 583)
  - Peace, Happines and Prosperity Institute, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 584)
  - Pearce, Richard E. (*), 1934-1978 (Box 17, Folder 585)
  - Ped-Peng (Box 17, Folder 586)
  - Peña, Joseph A. (*), 1950-1953, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 587-589)
  - Penn-Pere (Box 17, Folder 590)
  - Perf-Perl (Box 17, Folder 591)
  - Perkins, James A. (*), 1951, 1963-1976, undated (Box 17, Folder 592-593)
  - Perkins, Milo (*), 1942-1953 (Box 18, Folder 594-597)
    See also: box 23, folder 792-799
  - Pero-Peters (Box 18, Folder 598)
  - Peterso (Box 18, Folder 599)
  - Pett-Pf (Box 18, Folder 600)
  - Pfeiffer, George, 3rd (*), 1947-1949, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 601)
  - Phe-Phil (Box 18, Folder 602)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (*), 1970-1976 (Box 18, Folder 603-604)
  - Phip-Pil (Box 18, Folder 605)
  - Pickrel, Paul (*), 1948, 1964-1965, undated (Box 18, Folder 606-607)
  - Pierce, Ponchitta (*), 1971, undated (Box 18, Folder 608)
  - Pin-Pog (Box 18, Folder 609)
  - Players (*), 1948-1951 (Box 18, Folder 610)
  - Poi-Poo (Box 18, Folder 611)
  - Ponte, Lowell (*), 1970-1971 (Box 18, Folder 612-613)
  - Pop (Box 18, Folder 614)
  - Por (Box 18, Folder 615)
  - Pos-Pow (Box 18, Folder 616)
  - Pra-Presc (Box 18, Folder 617)
  - Prest-Pric (Box 18, Folder 618)
  - Preston, Eleanor (Mrs. Donald Barnes) (*), 1968-1971 (Box 18, Folder 619)
  - Price, Donald K. (*), 1943, 1946-1952 (Box 18, Folder 620-621)
  - Prin-Pro (Box 18, Folder 622)
  - Pringle, John D. (*), 1946-1950 (Box 18, Folder 623)
  - Progressive Democratic Party of Texas
    See: box 5, folder 141-149 See: box 7, folder 233 See: box 15, folder 511 See: box 15, folder 518 See: box 25, folder 876
  - Pry-Pul (Box 18, Folder 624)
  - Public Broadcasting Laboratory (*), 1968-1969 (Box 18, Folder 625-626)
    See also: box 16, folder 529-530
  - Puget Sound, University of (*), 1967-1970 (Box 18, Folder 627)
  - Pur-Py (Box 18, Folder 628)
  - 'P' unidentified (Box 18, Folder 629)
  - Q (Box 18, Folder 630)
  - Rab-Rag (Box 19, Folder 631)
  - Radcliffe College (*), 1950, 1961-1964 (Box 19, Folder 632)
  - Rai-Raj (Box 19, Folder 633)
  - Ram-Rand (Box 19, Folder 634)
  - Rank-Ras (Box 19, Folder 635)
  - Rat-Ray (Box 19, Folder 636)
  - Rea-Rec (Box 19, Folder 637)
  - Reader's Digest, 1945, 1968-1970 (Box 19, Folder 638)
    See also: box 6, folder 188
  - Red-Ree (Box 19, Folder 639)
  - Ref-Reil (Box 19, Folder 640)
  - Rein-Rep (Box 19, Folder 641)
  - Res-Rex (Box 19, Folder 642)
  - Retina Foundation (*), 1972-1974 (Box 19, Folder 643-644)
  - Rey-Rh (Box 19, Folder 645)
  - Rezendes, Dennis (*), 1969-1976 (Box 19, Folder 646-647)
  - Rhodes Scholarships (*), 1935-1977 (Box 19, Folder 648)
  - Rib-Ric (Box 19, Folder 649)
  - Rid-Rigg (Box 19, Folder 650)
  - Righ-Rip (Box 19, Folder 651)
  - Rit-Roberts (Box 19, Folder 652)
  - Robertso (Box 19, Folder 653)
  - Robertson, Nathan (*), 1946-1950, undated (Box 19, Folder 654)
  - Robi-Robs (Box 19, Folder 655)
  - Roch (Box 19, Folder 656)
  - Rock (Box 19, Folder 657)
  - Rockefeller, Winthrop
    See: box 24, folder 860
  - Rod-Roe (Box 19, Folder 658)
  - Rog-Rol (Box 19, Folder 659)
  - Ron-Roo (Box 19, Folder 660)
  - Roosevelt, Belle (Mrs. Kermit) (*), 1955-1956 (Box 19, Folder 661-662)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor
    See: box 1, folder 17
  - Roosevelt, Kermit, 1950, 1956, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 663)
  - Ror-Rosenb (Box 19, Folder 664)
  - Rose, Frederick P. (*), 1967-1975 (Box 19, Folder 665)
  - Rosent (Box 19, Folder 666)
  - Rosenw-Rosenz (Box 19, Folder 667)
  - Ross-Roste (Box 20, Folder 668)
  - Rosto-Rota (Box 20, Folder 669)
  - Rostow, Eugene V. (*), 1946-1972 (Box 20, Folder 670)
  - Roth-Rov (Box 20, Folder 671)
  - Roth, William V., 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 672)
  - Row-Rube (Box 20, Folder 673)
  - Rubi-Rud (Box 20, Folder 674)
  - Rue-Rush (Box 20, Folder 675)
  - Rusk-Russa (Box 20, Folder 676)
  - Russell, B-J (Box 20, Folder 677)
  - Russel, M-V (Box 20, Folder 678)
  - Rust-Ry (Box 20, Folder 679)
  - 'R' unidentified (Box 20, Folder 680)
  - Saa-Sag (Box 20, Folder 681)
  - Sai (Box 20, Folder 682)
  - Sal (Box 20, Folder 683)
  - Salzburg Seminar in American Studies (*), 1956-1967, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 684-685)
  - Sam (Box 20, Folder 686)
  - San (Box 20, Folder 687)
  - Sar-Sea (Box 20, Folder 688)
  - Saxton, Mark (*), 1950, 1965-1973 (Box 20, Folder 689-690)
  - Scha-Scher (Box 20, Folder 691)
  - Scherl, Donald J., 1968 (Box 20, Folder 692)
  - Scheu-Schi (Box 20, Folder 693)
  - Schl-Schm (Box 20, Folder 694)
  - Schn (Box 20, Folder 695)
  - Scho-Schu (Box 20, Folder 696)
  - Schw (Box 20, Folder 697)
  - Sci-Scu (Box 20, Folder 698)
  - Sea-Seg (Box 20, Folder 699)
  - Sei-Sell (Box 20, Folder 700)
  - Selt-Sey (Box 20, Folder 701)
  - Sha (Box 20, Folder 702)
  - Shea-Shef (Box 20, Folder 703)
  - Sheehan, Edward R.F. (*), 1964-1965 (Box 20, Folder 704)
  - Shel-Shn (Box 21, Folder 705)
  - Shob-Shoe (Box 21, Folder 706)
  - Shor-Sie (Box 21, Folder 707)
  - Silb-Silh (Box 21, Folder 708)
  - Sill-Silvers (Box 21, Folder 709)
  - Silverst-Simm (Box 21, Folder 710)
  - Simo-Sir (Box 21, Folder 711)
  - Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1964-1976 (Box 21, Folder 712)
  - Sizer, Theodore
    See: box 10, folder 321-322
  - Sk-Sm (Box 21, Folder 713)
  - Sloane, William (*), 1951-1953, 1965-1970 (Box 21, Folder 714-715)
  - Smith, A-C (Box 21, Folder 716)
  - Smith, D-J (Box 21, Folder 717)
  - Smith, L-R (Box 21, Folder 718)
  - Smith, Robert W. (*), 1968-1973 (Box 21, Folder 719-720)
  - Smith, Russell (*), 1947-1953 (Box 21, Folder 721)
  - Smith, S-W (Box 21, Folder 722)
  - Smith College (*), 1950, 1958 (Box 21, Folder 723)
  - Sn-Sole (Box 21, Folder 724)
  - Solw-Sou (Box 21, Folder 725)
  - Sorensen, Theodore C. (*), 1960 (Box 21, Folder 726)
  - Spa-Spe (Box 21, Folder 727)
  - Spi-Stad (Box 21, Folder 728)
  - Stah-Stap (Box 21, Folder 729)
  - Stanford University (*), 1966-1975 (Box 21, Folder 730)
  - Star-Stav (Box 21, Folder 731)
  - Stea-Stee (Box 21, Folder 732)
  - Stef-Steg (Box 21, Folder 733)
  - Stei-Stel (Box 21, Folder 734)
  - Sten-Stern (Box 21, Folder 735)
  - Sternl-Stil (Box 21, Folder 736)
  - Stevenson, Adlai E. (*), 1952-1965, undated (Box 21, Folder 737)
    See also: box 2, folder 57 See also: box 6, folder 189 See also: box 15, folder 495-496 See also: box 15, folder 507 See also: box 24, folder 824 See also: box 25, folder 868
  - Stillman, Edmund O. (*), 1959, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 738)
  - Stin-Stol (Box 21, Folder 739)
  - Stone-Stong (Box 21, Folder 740)
  - Stone, William T. (*), 1944-1951 (Box 21, Folder 741)
  - Stoney, George C., 1942-1968 (Box 21, Folder 742)
  - Stony-Stow (Box 21, Folder 743)
  - Stott, William M. (*), 1970-1977, undated (Box 21, Folder 744)
  - Stowe, Leland (*), 1955-1978 (Box 21, Folder 745)
  - Stra (Box 21, Folder 746)
  - Straus, Donald B., 1963, 1969-1972 (Box 21, Folder 747)
  - Stri-Stry (Box 22, Folder 748)
  - Strouse, Norman H. (*), 1965-1972 (Box 22, Folder 749)
  - Stu-Sug (Box 22, Folder 750)
  - Stuart, Reginald (*), 1971 (Box 22, Folder 751)
  - Sul (Box 22, Folder 752)
  - Sum-Sut (Box 22, Folder 753)
  - Sw (Box 22, Folder 754)
  - Sy-Sz (Box 22, Folder 755)
  - 'S' unidentified (Box 22, Folder 756)
  - Tab-Talb (Box 22, Folder 757)
  - Tall-Tata (Box 22, Folder 758)
  - Tant, Charles (*), 1944-1950, undated (Box 22, Folder 759-761)
  - Tate-Taw (Box 22, Folder 762)
  - Taylor, C-H (Box 22, Folder 763)
  - Taylor, P-T (Box 22, Folder 764)
  - Te (Box 22, Folder 765)
  - Tha-Thoman (Box 22, Folder 766)
  - Thomas (Box 22, Folder 767)
  - Thomas, Evan (*), 1948, 1959-1978, undated (Box 22, Folder 768-770)
  - Thompson, E-M (Box 22, Folder 771)
  - Thompson, S (Box 22, Folder 772)
  - Thor-Thu (Box 22, Folder 773)
  - Tib-Til (Box 22, Folder 774)
  - Tim-Tob (Box 22, Folder 775)
  - Tod-Toy (Box 22, Folder 776)
  - Torok, Lou (*), 1970-1974 (Box 22, Folder 777)
  - Tra-Tri (Box 22, Folder 778)
  - Trinity College, Hartford, Connecticut, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 779)
  - Tro-Ts (Box 22, Folder 780)
  - Tuc-Tum (Box 22, Folder 781)
  - Tun-Tut (Box 22, Folder 782)
  - Tw-Ty (Box 22, Folder 783)
  - Twombly, Michael, 1969-1970 (Box 22, Folder 784)
  - 'T' unidentified (Box 22, Folder 785)
  - Ul-Unit (Box 23, Folder 786)
  - Ungeheuer, Friedel, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 787)
  - United States Government: general (*), 1935-1972 (Box 23, Folder 788-792)
  - United States Government: Department of Agriculture, 1941-1972 (Box 23, Folder 793)
  - United States Government: Department of Agriculture, Farm Security Administration (*), 1937-1944, undated (Box 23, Folder 794-795)
  - United States Government: Board of Economic Warfare (*), 1942-1944 (Box 23, Folder 796-799)
    See also: box 8, folder 241-246 See also: box 18, folder 594-597
  - United States Government: Federal Communications Commission, 1959-1960 (Box 23, Folder 800)
  - United States Government: Foreign Economic Administration (*), 1943-1945 (Box 23, Folder 801-805)
    See also: box 2, folder 47 See also: box 2, folder 54 See also: box 7, folder 206 See also: box 8, folder 241-246 See also: box 12, folder 382 See also: box 14, folder 459-462 See also: box 21, folder 741 See also: box 25, folder 861
  - United States Government: Department of State (*), 1944-1971 (Box 23, Folder 806-807)
    See also: box 6, folder 200
  - United States Information Agency (*), 1959-1975 (Box 23, Folder 808-812)
  - United World Federalists, Inc. (*), 1948-1953, undated (Box 23, Folder 813-817)
  - Univ-Ur (Box 23, Folder 818)
  - Vai-Vang (Box 24, Folder 819)
  - Van Dusen, Lewis H., Jr. (*), 1947, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 820)
  - Vani-Vau (Box 24, Folder 821)
  - Vaugn, Burton E. (*), 1945-1970 (Box 24, Folder 822)
  - Ve-Vik (Box 24, Folder 823)
  - Vil-Volk (Box 24, Folder 824)
  - Volt-Vu (Box 24, Folder 825)
  - Von Blon, Philip (*), 1967-1971 (Box 24, Folder 826)
  - Wag-Wale (Box 24, Folder 827)
  - Walk (Box 24, Folder 828)
  - Wall-Wals (Box 24, Folder 829)
  - Wallace, DeWitt (*), 1963-1975 (Box 24, Folder 830)
  - Waller, Theodore (*), 1946-1972, 1978, undated (Box 24, Folder 831)
    See also: box 23, folder 813-817
  - Walt-Warb (Box 24, Folder 832)
  - War Control Planners, Inc., 1968 (Box 24, Folder 833)
  - Ward (Box 24, Folder 834)
  - Warl-Warr (Box 24, Folder 835)
  - Was-Watr (Box 24, Folder 836)
  - Wats (Box 24, Folder 837)
  - Watt-Weal (Box 24, Folder 838)
  - Weav (Box 24, Folder 839)
  - Webb-Webe (Box 24, Folder 840)
  - Webs-Weed (Box 24, Folder 841)
  - Week-Weg (Box 24, Folder 842)
  - Weh-Wei (Box 24, Folder 843)
  - Wel-Wend (Box 24, Folder 844)
  - Wells, Rosa F., 1947-1952 (Box 24, Folder 845)
  - Weng (Box 24, Folder 846)
  - Wer-Wess (Box 24, Folder 847)
  - West (Box 24, Folder 848)
  - Wex-Whita (Box 24, Folder 849)
  - White (Box 24, Folder 850)
  - Whitm-Whitw (Box 24, Folder 851)
  - Whitney (John Hay) Foundation (*), 1950-1955 (Box 24, Folder 852)
  - Who-Why (Box 24, Folder 853)
  - Wic-Wig (Box 24, Folder 854)
  - Wiebe, Robert H., undated (Box 24, Folder 855)
  - Wila-Wild (Box 24, Folder 856)
  - Wile-William (Box 24, Folder 857)
  - Williams, A-R (Box 24, Folder 858)
  - Williams, S - W (Box 24, Folder 859)
  - Williamsburg International Assembly, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 860)
  - Williamso-Wills (Box 25, Folder 861)
  - Wilson, D-I (Box 25, Folder 862)
  - Wilson, Finley (*), 1960-1978 (Box 25, Folder 863)
  - Wilson, J (Box 25, Folder 864)
  - Wilson, K-W (Box 25, Folder 865)
  - Wim-Wing (Box 25, Folder 866)
  - Winh-Winw (Box 25, Folder 867)
  - Wir-Wisc (Box 25, Folder 868)
  - Wisconsin-Green Bay, University of (*), 1969-1974 (Box 25, Folder 869)
  - Wiss-Wof (Box 25, Folder 870)
  - Woh-Wolfe (Box 25, Folder 871)
  - Wolff-Woodb (Box 25, Folder 872)
  - Woods-Woody (Box 25, Folder 873)
  - Wor-Wou (Box 25, Folder 874)
  - Wre-Wrig (Box 25, Folder 875)
  - Wright, Herman (*), undated (Box 25, Folder 876)
  - Writ (Box 25, Folder 877)
  - Wu-Wy (Box 25, Folder 878)
  - Wyeth, M.S. ("Buz"), Jr. (*), 1970-1978 (Box 25, Folder 879)
  - 'W' unidentified (Box 25, Folder 880)
  - Ya-Yod (Box 25, Folder 881)
  - Yale University (*), 1968-1977, undated (Box 25, Folder 882-883)
    See also: box 3, folder 74
  - Yale University Press (*), 1971-1977 (Box 25, Folder 884)
  - Yarbrough, Tom (*), 1934-1968, undated (Box 25, Folder 885)
  - Yos-Young, H (Box 25, Folder 886)
  - Young, J-Yu (Box 25, Folder 887)
  - 'Y' unidentified (Box 25, Folder 888)
  - Z (Box 25, Folder 889)
  - Zimmerman, W. David
    See: box 7, folder 226
  - Zwerdling, Daniel, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 890)
  - Unidentified, 1928-1977, undated (Box 25, Folder 891-892)
- Family Correspondence, 1907-1978, undated; Series II; .75 linear feet (2 boxes)
  This series contains Fischer's correspondence with his family, and is arranged chronologically.Also included are a few letters addressed to his parents and daughters from third parties. Correspondence addressed to Elizabeth (Wilson) Fischer by non-family members has been incorporated into Series I.
  - 1907-1908, 1915, 1924 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - 1928 July-1929 September (Box 26, Folder 2-8)
  - 1930-1931 (Box 26, Folder 9-10)
  - 1933 May-1935 December (Box 26, Folder 11-22)
  - 1936 January-August (Box 26, Folder 23-24)
  - 1937 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - 1938-1944 September (Box 27, Folder 26-31)
  - 1945-1960-1961 January (Box 27, Folder 32-38)
  - 1961 March-December (Box 27, Folder 39)
  - 1962-1978 (Box 27, Folder 40-44)
  - undated (Box 27, Folder 45-48)
- Subject Files, 1935-1978, undated; Series III; 4 linear feet (10 boxes)
  This series contains materials such as clippings, office memoranda, offprints, and brochures, collected and organized by Fischer under various headings. They are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Appalachia, 1967, 1970-1977, undated (Box 28, Folder 1-4)
  - Arts, 1961-1978, undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1963, 1975, undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Best Articles and Stories, Inc., 1958-1960, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Boats, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Brookings Institute, 1966-1977 (Box 28, Folder 9-10)
  - California Western Railroad, 1967, undated (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Cary, Joyce, 1949-1964, undated (Box 28, Folder 12-14)
  - Century Association, 1952-1977 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Christmas list, 1971-1975, undated (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - College of the Atlantic, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Colleges and universities, 1960-1976, undated (Box 29, Folder 18-20)
  - Columbia Bicentennial on Federalism, 1953-1954 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Conservation and ecology, 1957-1975, undated (Box 29, Folder 22-24)
  - Editing and publishing, 1947-1965 (Box 29, Folder 25-27)
  - Editing and publishing, 1966-1975, undated (Box 30, Folder 28-33)
  - Education, 1961-1968 (Box 30, Folder 34)
  - Europe, 1949-1967, undated (Box 30, Folder 35)
  - Farm problem, 1955-1971 (Box 30, Folder 36-37)
  - Father Fabian-Decline and Fall of the U.S., 1959-1969, undated (Box 30, Folder 38)
  - Federal service and patronage, 1948-1956 (Box 30, Folder 39)
  - Florida, undated (Box 30, Folder 40)
  - Government, 1947-1972, undated (Box 31, Folder 41)
  - Great Britain, 1937-1975, undated (Box 31, Folder 42-44)
  - Heroes, 1953-1962 (Box 31, Folder 45)
  - Humor, 1956-1971 (Box 31, Folder 46)
  - India, 1943-1968, undated (Box 31, Folder 47-49)
  - Iran, 1961-1967, undated (Box 31, Folder 50-52)
  - Japan, 1963-1971, undated (Box 31, Folder 53-54)
  - Journalism, 1953-1970, undated (Box 32, Folder 55-57)
  - Markle Foundation, 1956-1960 (Box 32, Folder 58)
  - Museums, 1956-1960, undated (Box 32, Folder 59-60)
  - National Governors' Conference, the Virgin Islands, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 61)
  - New England, 1968-1974, undated (Box 32, Folder 62)
  - New Left, 1965-1968, undated (Box 32, Folder 63)
  - Oil and energy, 1947-1959, undated (Box 32, Folder 64)
  - Oxford University, 1964-1972, undated (Box 32, Folder 65)
  - Politics and politicians, 1956-1976, undated (Box 32, Folder 66-67)
  - Portugal, 1971-1972, undated (Box 33, Folder 68-69)
  - President's National Advisory Committee on Rural Poverty, 1965-1967, undated (Box 33, Folder 70-77)
  - Race relations, 1964-1970, undated (Box 34, Folder 78)
  - Rothko, Mark, 1961-1970, undated (Box 34, Folder 79)
  - Salzburg Seminar in American Studies, 1955-1973, undated (Box 34, Folder 80-83)
  - Samothrace, 1955-1959, undated (Box 34, Folder 84-85)
  - Stevenson, Adlai, 1952-1956, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 86-90)
  - Stinginess, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 91)
  - Taxes and tax reform, 1961-1972, undated (Box 35, Folder 92-93)
  - Television, 1962-1972, n.d (Box 35, Folder 94-98)
  - Travel, 1957-1978, undated (Box 35, Folder 99-100)
  - U.S.S.R., 1959-1962, undated (Box 35, Folder 101)
  - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration, Mission to the Ukraine, 1946 March-November (Box 35, Folder 102-103)
  - United States Army War College, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 104-105)
  - United States Army War College, 1958 (Box 36, Folder 106)
  - United States Government: Board of Economic Warfare, 1942-1948, undated (Box 36, Folder 107-111)
  - United States Government: Farm Security Administation, 1937-1941, undated (Box 36, Folder 112-115)
  - United States Government: Foreign Economic Administration, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 116-117)
  - United States Government: Resettlement Administration, 1935-1940, undated (Box 36, Folder 118-119)
  - United World Federalists, 1948-1949 January (Box 36, Folder 120)
  - United World Federalists, 1949 March-1950 (Box 37, Folder 121)
  - The University in developing countries, 1965-1966 (Box 37, Folder 122)
  - Urban problems, 1963-1976, undated (Box 37, Folder 123)
  - Violence, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 124)
  - West Indies, 1947-1977, undated (Box 37, Folder 125-126)
  - White House Confernece on International Cooperation, 1965 (Box 37, Folder 127)
  - Wilson (Woodrow) Memorial, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 128)
  - Wines, undated (Box 37, Folder 129)
  - World economy, 1938-1972, undated (Box 37, Folder 130)
  - Yale University, 1968-1971 (Box 37, Folder 131)
  - Yugoslavia, 1958-1969, undated (Box 37, Folder 132-134)
  - Miscellaneous, 1935-1976, undated (Box 37, Folder 135-138)
- Writings, 1928-1978, undated; Series IV; 4.75 lienar feet (12 boxes, microfilm)
  WRITINGS is divided up into three sections. Books is arranged alphabetically by title. Included are drafts and proofs of several books and printed editions of others, as well as some promotional material, reviews, and working files of background materials.
  Articles is composed of drafts, offprints, and reprinted versions of many of Fischer's magazine articles, especially his "Easy Chair" column. The articles are arranged chronologically, and the first place of publication only, if other than Harper's has been noted. Appended to the register as Appendix B is a partial list of articles by Fischer which have appeared in Harper's. Not all of these are included in the papers. Refer to finding aid in repository for Appendix B. Consult Reference Archivist for assistance.
  Early newspaper articles written by Fischer and copies of newspapers he edited have been microfilmed (see MICROFILM HM 120) and the originals destroyed. Not all of the articles carry Fischer's by-line but since they were preserved by his family it seems likely that they were indeed written by Fischer.
  Speeches is also arranged chronologically. Notes for a few speeches, drafts of others, and in several cases printed versions comprise the section. Included are statements by Fischer before several Senate committees, a number of commencement addresses, and various guest lectures before university and professional organizations. (Notes and partial drafts of Fischer's lectures at the Salzburg Seminar on American Studies (1957) can be found in Series I, folder 684).
  - Books
    - America's Master Plan (British edition of Master Plan U.S.A. ), 1951 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - From the High Plains: draft, [pre-1978] (Box 38, Folder 2-13)
    - From the High Plains: proofs, 1978 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - From the High Plains: proofs, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 15-27)
    - From the High Plains: promotion and reviews, 1978-1979 (Box 39, Folder 28-28a)
    - From the High Plains: working files, Circa 1960-1978 (Box 39, Folder 29)
    - From the High Plains: working files, Circa 1960-1978 (Box 40, Folder 30-33)
    - Master Plan U.S.A.: reviews, 1951 (Box 40, Folder 34)
    - "The Money System": draft, [ca. 1933-1934] (Box 40, Folder 35-36)
    - "The Money System": later draft, [ca. 1933-1934] (Box 40, Folder 37-40)
    - Six in the Easy Chair: draft, [pre-1973] (Box 41, Folder 41-43)
    - Six in the Easy Chair: draft, 1973 (Box 41, Folder 44-47)
    - Six in the Easy Chair: draft, 1973 (Box 41, Folder 48-49)
    - Six in the Easy Chair: promotion and reviews, 1973-1974 (Box 41, Folder 50)
    - Six in the Easy Chair: working files, [pre-1973] (Box 41, Folder 51-54)
    - The Stupidity Problem and Other Harassments: reviews, 1964 (Box 41, Folder 55)
    - Vital Signs, U.S.A.: draft, [pre-1975] (Box 41, Folder 56-62)
    - Vital Signs, U.S.A.: draft, [pre-1975] (Box 42, Folder 63)
    - Vital Signs, U.S.A.: draft, [1974] (Box 42, Folder 64-69)
    - Vital Signs, U.S.A.: proofs, 1974-1975 (Box 42, Folder 70-71)
    - Vital Signs, U.S.A.: promotion and reviews, 1975-1976 (Box 42, Folder 72-73)
    - Vital Signs, U.S.A.: working files, [ca. 1973-1974] (Box 42, Folder 74-75)
    - Why They Behave Like Russians, 1946 (Box 43, Folder 76)
    - Why They Behave Like Russians (Dutch), [post-1946] (Box 43, Folder 77)
    - Why They Behave Like Russians (Danish), 1947 (Box 43, Folder 78)
    - Why They Behave Like Russians (French), 1947 (Box 43, Folder 79)
    - Why They Behave Like Russians (Swedish), 1947 (Box 43, Folder 80)
    - Why They Behave Like Russians (Norwegian), 1948 (Box 44, Folder 81)
    - Why They Behave Like Russians (German), 1948 (Box 44, Folder 82)
    - Why They Behave Like Russians (German), 1949 (Box 44, Folder 83)
    - Why They Behave Like Russians: promotion and reviews, 1946-1948 (Box 44, Folder 84-88)
  - Articles
    - Early newspaper articles, 1924, 1926-1937, 1947, undated (Box 44, Folder 84-88)
      General
      See: MICROFILM HM 120
    - "The Way of Athletic Dollars," The Sooner Magazine, 1930 March (Box 45, Folder 89)
    - "Patriot's Catechism," The New Republic, 1932 October 12 (Box 45, Folder 90)
    - "A Conservative Looks at the Labour Child": draft, [ca. 1933-1935] (Box 45, Folder 91)
    - "The Oxford Legend": draft, [ca. 1933-1935] (Box 45, Folder 92)
    - "Ruskin Dances": draft, [ca.1933-1935] (Box 45, Folder 93)
    - The Lincoln Imp (edited by J. Fischer), 1934 Mar, Jun, December (Box 45, Folder 94)
    - The Oxford Forward (edited by J. Fischer), 1934 November (Box 45, Folder 95)
    - "Election in the Saar," The Nation, 1935 January 23 (Box 45, Folder 96)